BHUMIKA BERGMAN

Computer Engineer

Pingree Grove, IL 60140 • 224-595-5222 bbergman@elgin.edu • Portfolio • Github Repositories

OBJECTIVE

Driven and creative professional with over 5 years of experience in creating Websites, Web Applications, and cross-platform Desktop Applications, seeking to grow in the Senior Web Developer and UX/UI Designer role; offering expertise in Web Design, Web Development, Accessibility, and SEO strategies.

EMPLOYMENT

Elgin Community College

Digital Accessibility Developer

11/2020 - PRESENT

- Boosted main website accessibility by 15% in 4 months and maintained WCAG 2.0 AA compliance.
- Utilized Jira and demonstrated excellent multi-tasking skills by taking on multiple tasks as needed by the
 department to meet the project deadline.
- Created webpages, managed users in the CMS, and performed content management tasks.
- Troubleshoot website bugs and accessibility issues, provided solutions, and assisted with the implementation.
- Worked as a part of the team to optimize the website for page load speed and SEO to increase site visibility.
- Wrote reusable, scalable, and accessible code.

National Institute for Optimal Wellness

Front-end Web Developer & Manager

09/2019 - 10/2020

- Achieved excellent user experience by creating a fully responsive website with a user-friendly UI/UX, student portal, and eCommerce.
- Dramatically *reduced page load time* by 20% by debugging and optimizing the website by resizing and compressing the images/videos, adding asynchronous and defer loading to JS and CSS files, minifying the JS and CSS files, etc.
- Develop concepts, control project flow, and ensure deliverable milestones are met.

Office Depot

Service Advisor 09/2019 – 10/2020

- Maintaining an average of 9/10 in customer experience surveys by proactively engaging customers to drive the sale
 of total solutions and properly assessing customer needs to ensure satisfaction in every interaction.
- Offered 100% satisfaction to all customers by preparing orders correctly and within the quoted timeline.
- Building relationships with customers to increase the likelihood of repeat business.
- Offered back up to colleagues and helped train new employees in design and printing.

Primitius International

Freelance Application Developer

01/2018 - 11/2018

- Succeeded in *reducing time* to analyze and evaluate a natural health survey in Jotform *by 67%* by creating a cross-platform survey analyzer application.
- Constructed the application on the electron framework using HTML/CSS and JavaScript while assuring the *maintainability* of the code.
- Focused on *customer demands* and exceeded customer requirements.

New Eden School of Natural Health and Herbal Studies

Portal Management Administration Assistant

03/2016 - 04/2017

- Provided front-end web development skills to a team developing a WordPress-based student portal.
- Reduced the duration of the project by approximately 15 days by attaining the user requirements from the client.

- Optimized the system performance by 10% by identifying the bugs while assisting the students with technical inquiries.
- Applied excellent *problem-solving and administration skills* while assisting the portal manager to manage students.

EDUCATION

York University, Canada

09/2013 - 02/2018

Bachelor of Engineering(B.Eng.), Special Honours Computer Engineering, Major GPA: 3.2

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: Proficient in Java, JavaScript, HTML5, and CSS. Intermediate in C, Python, and MongoDB.

Version Control: Git

Applications: MS Office, Eclipse, Android Studio, MATLAB, GoormIDE, VS Code, Photoshop, InDesign, Commonlook PDF

Platforms: Jira, Confluence, Google Analytics, Google Search Console, Funnelback, Siteimprove, Jotform, WordPress,

Weebly, TerminalFour

Frameworks: Electron, Bootstrap, Node.js, Express

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Transcript Generator (Electron, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JSON)

01/2021 - 03/2021

- Designed a **desktop transcript generator application** for an online school using the Electron framework.
- Dramatically reduced user errors by pulling data from a JSON file and automating the calculations.
- Utilized *scalable code design* to accommodate future changes or additions to the school curriculum.

Event Counter Plus (JavaScript, HTML, CSS, EJS, Express)

08/2019 - 07/2020

- Creating an *interactive web application* on the Express framework using EJS templates that calculates the time passed since the event and calculates the time left until the next monthly/yearly anniversary.
- Configuring MongoDB database to store information about users and events.
- Increasing the app performance by using RESTful routes for cleaner URLs, Git for version control, and bootstrap 4 for the responsive web design.

AMD Application (Object Oriented Programming, Java, Android, Firebase)

09/2016 - 04/2017

- Implemented an Android application for AMD (Age-related macular degeneration) patients.
- Reduced the app's memory footprint by using a firebase database to manipulate the data.
- Wrote *reliable and maintainable* code, while focusing on customer demands.
- Provided excellent user experience by developing both voice recognition and touch-based UI.

Hospital Messenger System (Object Oriented Programming, Java)

09/2016 - 12/2016

- Developed a secure hospital messenger system in Java which allowed the clients to create groups and send text messages to the group.
- Improved verification and validation of the system by applying *requirements elicitation concepts*.
- Optimized the system by 27% by finding bugs using acceptance tests and use cases.
- Assured usability and scalability of the product, while meeting user requirements.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE AND AWARDS

- Volunteering: Volunteered as a peer mentor at Lassonde School of Engineering.
- **Final year capstone project:** Awarded "Patel Family Capstone Project Award" for winning the 2nd prize in the final year capstone project for AMD application.

SOFT SKILLS

- Hard worker, quick learner, eager to further knowledge and skills
- Self-motivated; able to learn on own initiative
- Excellent verbal and written communication skills while working with colleagues, clients, and supervisors
- Able and willing to assist co-workers and supervisors in a cooperative manner
- Excellent organizational, time management, and problem-solving skills
- Detail-oriented, creative, critical thinker, and able to work under pressure in a team to meet deadlines